<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Developement on Vincent Demeester</title>
    <link>http://vincent.demeester.fr/categories/developement/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Developement on Vincent Demeester</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>fr-fr</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vincent.demeester.fr/categories/developement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang testing — golden file</title>
      <link>http://vincent.demeester.fr/posts/2017-04-22-golang-testing-golden-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vincent.demeester.fr/posts/2017-04-22-golang-testing-golden-file/</guid>
      <description>Tests are all about maintainability and readability. You want the least visual noise possible and it should not be a hassle to maintain. When testing functions that output a long of string, in case of a command line output testing, readability and maintainance tend to be tricky to achieve. The problem  As an example let&#39;s say we want to test out the output of a command that displays a list as a table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang testing — functional arguments for wonderful builders</title>
      <link>http://vincent.demeester.fr/posts/2017-01-01-go-testing-functionnal-builders/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vincent.demeester.fr/posts/2017-01-01-go-testing-functionnal-builders/</guid>
      <description>Programming is not easy; even the best programmers are incapable of writing programs that work exactly as intended every time. Therefore an important part of the software development process is testing. Writing tests for our code is a good way to ensure quality and improve reliability.   Go programs, when properly implemented, are fairly simple to test programatically. The testing built-in library and the features of the language itself offer plenty of ways to write good tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migration vers hugo</title>
      <link>http://vincent.demeester.fr/posts/2015-05-09-migration-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vincent.demeester.fr/posts/2015-05-09-migration-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Et voilà, une semaine après m&#39;être remis en route sur ce blog, je fais déjà une migration &amp;gt;_&amp;lt;. Je me suis rendu compte que Jekyll m&#39;énervait un peu, et comme je suis à fond dans go en ce moment, j&#39;ai regardé du côté des générateurs de sites static et Hugo a clairement retenu mon attention. Pourquoi Hugo ?   Make the Web Fun Again  Introducing Hugo, a new idea around making website creation simple again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orgmode et Jekyll</title>
      <link>http://vincent.demeester.fr/posts/2015-05-01-orgmode-et-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vincent.demeester.fr/posts/2015-05-01-orgmode-et-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>Un peu plus d&#39;un an..  .. que je n&#39;ai rien posté ici. Le temps passe bien vite, mais c&#39;est plutôt une bonne chose. Je crois que quelque chose me manquait pour poster ici plus souvent.   Au niveau de mes points d&#39;entrées sur le web, je compte remettre un peu en route la partie blog de ce site et tourner shortbrain.org (ou autre) en un site plus &#34;documentation&#34; en me basant sur mes notes (powered by org-mode).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maven Tmpfs</title>
      <link>http://vincent.demeester.fr/posts/2013-09-08-maven-tmpfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vincent.demeester.fr/posts/2013-09-08-maven-tmpfs/</guid>
      <description>Je suis un utilisateur convaincu de [maven](), malgré ces défauts, le moto &amp;ldquo;Convention over configuration&amp;rdquo; me va vraiment bien. Que ce soit au boulot ou à la maison, j&amp;rsquo;ai plus d&amp;rsquo;ordinateurs équipés de ssd (ou de mémoire flash) que de disque traditionnel (mécanique ?). Pour augmenter un peu la durée de vie de ces disques SSD, j&amp;rsquo;ai cherché à savoir comment déporter le build de maven (qui, pour rappel, se passe dans le dossier target/) hors du SSD ; ici ce sera dans le dossier /tmp/ qui est monté en mémoire (merci tmpfs), mais on peut imaginer déporter ça sur un autre disque, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maven Release Gitflow</title>
      <link>http://vincent.demeester.fr/posts/2012-07-23-maven-release-gitflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vincent.demeester.fr/posts/2012-07-23-maven-release-gitflow/</guid>
      <description>I like a lot the gitflow way of managing project. When working on maven project, there is few great plugins that helps to get the work done. One of them is maven-release-plugin.
Inspired on this gist, I&amp;rsquo;ve come with a cool way of doing things (let say we want to release a 0.1 version of an artifact) :
Prepare the pom.xml. It needs &amp;lt;scm&amp;gt; entries, &amp;lt;distributionManagement&amp;gt; entries (to know where to deploy the release artifact) and few options for the maven-release-plugin :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jekyll Forman Guard Bundler</title>
      <link>http://vincent.demeester.fr/posts/2012-05-13-jekyll-foreman-guard-bundler/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vincent.demeester.fr/posts/2012-05-13-jekyll-foreman-guard-bundler/</guid>
      <description>This post is a quick &amp;ldquo;How did I setup my Jekyll environnement ?&amp;rdquo;. We are going all the tools that are quite awesome in Ruby.
Goal The goal is simple :
 I want to be able to install any dependent Gem with a on-liner command I want to be able to run a Jekyll server that auto updates.  We are going to play with : Bundler, Guard and foreman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gitolite quick and dirty mirror</title>
      <link>http://vincent.demeester.fr/posts/2012-05-08-gitolite-quick-and-dirty-mirror/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vincent.demeester.fr/posts/2012-05-08-gitolite-quick-and-dirty-mirror/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m running a gitolite instance on my personal server to manage my repositories (personnal, private or public) ; and I am quickly going to share with you how I setup a quick and dirty mirror feature.
First, I am using gitolite 3. The mirroring we are going to setup is not the supported mirroring built-in. We are going to implement a simplier way to set mirror thing :
 Write a custom gitolite command ; the idea is to be able to write git-config stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>